<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Activity 1 paragraph</title>
    <link href="/2021/06/05/Activity-1-paragraph/"/>
    <url>/2021/06/05/Activity-1-paragraph/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a practice writing piece during the second seminar of Professional Literacies, about the view outside the apartment window. It is required that we need to provide a detailed description of the scene.</p><!-- ![](/images/activity-1-paragraph-image1.jpeg) --><img src="/assets/images/activity-1-paragraph-image1.jpeg" width="286" height="440" /><h2 id="The-world-through-my-window"><a href="#The-world-through-my-window" class="headerlink" title="The world through my window"></a>The world through my window</h2><p>‘It is so blue’, when I suddenly raise my head and look outside, the blue sky of Melbourne just surprises me in a minute. Living in Carlton for a quite long time,  I never noticed that the view through my apartment window can be so amazing. The RMIT building is in front of where I live, and I can see quite a lot students walking in and out with their bags and holding their books. The Yarra tram passes by with a sound of bells. Also, there are two birds resting on my balcony, the interesting thing is that my cat Ray, who really has strange fantasy of being a bird, she would imitate the sound of bird every time when she sees the birds through the window.  It is also attractive to spend some time on observing the pedestrian crossing between my apartment building and RMIT building since there are a lot of people passing. I always think that observing others is quite an interesting reflection of my inner thoughts in some degree. Taking a glance further away, I can even see Melbourne Central, although I know it is quite near where I live.  When I look back, one of my cat is staring at me, at that moment, I cannot be more felicific.  </p><h2 id="Reflection-on-this-short-piece"><a href="#Reflection-on-this-short-piece" class="headerlink" title="Reflection on this short piece:"></a>Reflection on this short piece:</h2><ul><li>what there anything you learnt from doing this activity?</li><li>What did you find challenging about it/what easy?</li><li>What sort of language did you use?</li></ul><h2 id="My-reflection"><a href="#My-reflection" class="headerlink" title="My reflection:"></a>My reflection:</h2><p>How to arrange the structure of a passage in a short time is the most important thing I learnt through this activity. After listening and reviewing on other’s piece, I realised that in the writing, personal feeling and reflection can also be linked with objective view.</p><p>Secondly, it is not a easy task to provide something complete within 20 minutes, the time pressure is also a huge challenge for me to overcome since I’m always a slow typer.</p><p>Also, considering this is a piece about daily view and scene, so what I adopt is the language to describe things instead of academic or argumentative overall.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2021/06/04/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2021/06/04/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction and Reflection on the Job Set</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/24/example/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/24/example/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction-on-the-Job-Set"><a href="#Introduction-on-the-Job-Set" class="headerlink" title="Introduction on the Job Set"></a>Introduction on the Job Set</h2><p>This job set is mainly about my personal background and research experience in response to the requirement for PhD selection criteria in the Arts faculty of UniMelb and focuses on highlighting my research interest and advantages in perusing further study in the School and Language and Linguistics.</p><p>The set includes three parts, a Cover letter, CV and selection criteria respectively. The main purpose of the cover letter is to recommend me to the supervisor who is matching with my research interest and show my highlights in academic research and professional experience. The second part (CV) is mainly about detailed information about me, such as past educational background, publications, professional experience, research outcome and skills. Finally, the main focus of the response to selection criteria is to reflect how I meet each selection criteria in perusing for a PhD study in UniMelb. </p><p><a href="/assets/files/Wei-Gao-PL-PhD-CV.pdf">Rena’s Job Set👉</a></p><!-- Download buton --><p><a href="/assets/files/Wei-Gao-PL-PhD-CV.pdf" style="background: #32373c;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Download<a/>.</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Reflection-on-the-Job-Set"><a href="#Reflection-on-the-Job-Set" class="headerlink" title="Reflection on the Job Set"></a>Reflection on the Job Set</h2><ul><li>Challenges in designing this Job Set:</li></ul><p>First of all, the most challenging part in this job set is to suit myself in the requirement of assignment instead of a real PhD application. Since the genre and cover letter in the real selection is quite different with the requirements in this subject in many aspects. For example, in the CV required for a real PhD application, a section of briefly introduce proposed topic is necessary for the selection committee, while in this subject, the CV does not need to include this part. And I struggled with the different requirements a lot when I touch this job set at first.</p><ul><li>Get to work on this Job Set:</li></ul><p>However, after Janne’s advice and her suggestion during the several seminars, I felt much better at understanding the difference of this assignment between the real requirements in PhD application. So, I made several adjustments in drafting this job set. First, I cut several details in my CV, only kept the most relevant experience and highlights in my past research and academic experience. Also, the length of the cover letter was shortened to one page and become more concise in the whole content, and I didn’t include the research purpose which is actually required in the application. Furthermore, for the response to selection criteria, I modified a little bit on the overall structure in order to make it clearer since the requirements of the PhD selection of Arts is quite long and a lot of documents and supplementary materials are needed as well.</p><ul><li>More understanding on this kind of genre:</li></ul><p>After receiving the feedback, I realised that the Job Set has completely different purpose than the academic writing, which is short, appropriate and accurate in general tone, instead of listing much details or presenting deep understanding in certain position.</p><p>Thus, it suits me better in my future resume preparation as well as drafting for cover letter in emails to the target person (e.g. supervisor).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
