<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction and Reflection on interview report</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/24/Introduction-and-reflection-on-the-Interview-report/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/24/Introduction-and-reflection-on-the-Interview-report/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction-of-the-interview-report"><a href="#Introduction-of-the-interview-report" class="headerlink" title="Introduction of the interview report:"></a>Introduction of the interview report:</h2><p>This report investigates the impact of the COVID-19 on international students who are resident in Melbourne and how it changed their style of studying, social interaction and future work plan. All four interviewees are Master students from the School of Language and Linguistics. The interview adopts the semi-structured way to see their change and attitude towards the online learning and their social life as well as their future work choice in year 2020.</p><p>During the process of completing this assignment, four members in our group collaborative well although we basically depend on online communicate software to update on each other. Before we actually conducting the interview, I settled the topic and focus of this interview, then all the group members brainstormed on the interview questions collaboratively. Then, each of us is responsible for one part in the report and contacted our interviewees respectively.<br>During the process of each interview, four group members would all be in the Zoom session and after completing the interview, all members would listen to the recording again and find some interesting points to address in the report. Finally, after drafting the report, we improved the ability of collaborative work, especially in writing and conducting interview.</p><p><a href="/2021/05/20/interview-report/" style="background: #E74C3C;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Link to report<a/></p><h2 id="Reflection-of-the-interview-report"><a href="#Reflection-of-the-interview-report" class="headerlink" title="Reflection of the interview report:"></a>Reflection of the interview report:</h2><ul><li>Identify the interview focus is essential</li></ul><p>Before conducting this assignment, I have interview experience when I was the Research Assistant in the Australian Center. But I mainly help to collect data and analyse discourse data instead of design an interview individually by myself. When first dived into this report, I began to wonder what is worth interviewing for international students in Australian university since I hold such an identity myself. After a reflection on my own experience in the past year, I think to interest the impact of the pandemic on international students would be interesting and meaningful. Thus, I decided to set the topic as:</p><p class="note note-info">How COVID-19 Pandemic Affect Studying Abroad in Australian University: A Case of Master Students in School of Language and Linguistics</p><ul><li>Make everyone clear about their role</li></ul><p>To be honest, this is the most challenging part for me since the other three group members don’t have any interview or analysis experience, so it makes all members understanding their role in the first place is quite difficult. So, I use several times to show them the difference between interview and conversation and how to analyse interview discourse from an objective perspective. Besides, we also marked everyone’s part in a Google Doc so that the whole group could be much clearer about the whole process and progress of the report. Even four group members mainly worked remotely due to the post-pandemic reason, but the weekly meeting went go pretty smooth.</p><ul><li>Time management is everything</li></ul><p>When the group are working on the interview and the report, there are other assignments due at the same time, and after everyone finalized their part, I would look through all the report and correct some typos and grammar mistakes. Thus, it is essential to allocate the duty in a reasonable schedule. Through this assignment, I learned how to collaborate writing and interview others professionally, including all the processes from designing interview questions to finally doing the transcript.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>interview</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction and Reflection on the job set</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/24/introduction-and-reflection-on-the-job-set/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/24/introduction-and-reflection-on-the-job-set/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction-of-the-job-set"><a href="#Introduction-of-the-job-set" class="headerlink" title="Introduction of the job set:"></a>Introduction of the job set:</h2><p>This job set is mainly about my personal background and research experience in response to the requirement for PhD selection criteria in the Arts faculty of UniMelb and focuses on highlighting my research interest and advantages in perusing further study in the School and Language and Linguistics.</p><p>The set includes three parts, a Cover letter, CV and selection criteria respectively. The main purpose of the cover letter is to recommend me to the supervisor who is matching with my research interest and show my highlights in academic research and professional experience. The second part (CV) is mainly about detailed information about me, such as past educational background, publications, professional experience, research outcome and skills. Finally, the main focus of the response to selection criteria is to reflect how I meet each selection criteria in perusing for a PhD study in UniMelb. </p><p><a href="/2021/05/18/cover-letter/" style="background: #E74C3C;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Cover Letter<a/> <a href="/2021/05/18/cv/" style="background: #E74C3C;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >CV<a/> <a href="/2021/05/20/response/" style="background: #E74C3C;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Response to Graduate Attributes<a/></p><p><a href="/2021/05/18/cover-letter/" style="background: #32373c;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Cover Letter<a/>  </p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Reflection-on-the-job-set"><a href="#Reflection-on-the-job-set" class="headerlink" title="Reflection on the job set:"></a>Reflection on the job set:</h2><ul><li>Challenges in designing this job set:</li></ul><p>First of all, the most challenging part in this job set is to suit myself in the requirement of assignment instead of a real PhD application. Since the genre and cover letter in the real selection is quite different with the requirements in this subject in many aspects. For example, in the CV required for a real PhD application, a section of briefly introduce proposed topic is necessary for the selection committee, while in this subject, the CV does not need to include this part. And I struggled with the different requirements a lot when I touch this job set at first.</p><ul><li>Get to work on this job set:</li></ul><p>However, after Janne’s advice and her suggestion during the several seminars, I felt much better at understanding the difference of this assignment between the real requirements in PhD application. So, I made several adjustments in drafting this job set. First, I cut several details in my CV, only kept the most relevant experience and highlights in my past research and academic experience. Also, the length of the cover letter was shortened to one page and become more concise in the whole content, and I didn’t include the research purpose which is actually required in the application. Furthermore, for the response to selection criteria, I modified a little bit on the overall structure in order to make it clearer since the requirements of the PhD selection of Arts is quite long and a lot of documents and supplementary materials are needed as well.</p><ul><li>More understanding on this kind of genre:</li></ul><p>After receiving the feedback, I realised that the Job Set has completely different purpose than the academic writing, which is short, appropriate and accurate in general tone, instead of listing much details or presenting deep understanding in certain position.</p><p>Thus, it suits me better in my future resume preparation as well as drafting for cover letter in emails to the target person (e.g. supervisor).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>job-set</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Interview Report</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/20/interview-report/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/20/interview-report/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="How-the-COVID-19-Pandemic-Affects-Studying-Abroad-A-Case-of-Master-Students-in-School-of-Languages-and-Linguistics"><a href="#How-the-COVID-19-Pandemic-Affects-Studying-Abroad-A-Case-of-Master-Students-in-School-of-Languages-and-Linguistics" class="headerlink" title="How the COVID-19 Pandemic Affects Studying Abroad: A Case of Master Students in School of Languages and Linguistics"></a>How the COVID-19 Pandemic Affects Studying Abroad: A Case of Master Students in School of Languages and Linguistics</h1><h2 id="Executive-Summary"><a href="#Executive-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Executive Summary"></a>Executive Summary</h2><p>This report investigates the studying status and life experiences of current students of the University of Melbourne during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020, namely the School of Language and Linguistics. This interview report focuses on how the pandemic impacted the life of international students who were resident in Melbourne during their studying abroad life. It aims to discover the challenges in online learning, social life and working plan and provide recommendations for international students and staff in the School of Languages and Linguistics.</p><p>This research involved four master students in the School of Languages and Linguistics in conducting independent semi-structured interviews. We analysed their opinions and reflections on their studying experience, social life and working plan during the pandemic. Through this interview, we realised that the Chinese international students had encountered enormous challenges during the pandemic in Melbourne, such as barriers created by online learning and teaching. However, most participants still thought the subjects were valuable and practical for their future work preparation. As for social life and extracurricular activities, they reported that it was hard for them to participate in Melbourne activities due to the pandemic outbreak and the lockdown. Finally, we concluded with recommendations for international students, including studying, social life and working plan in their future study abroad life.</p><h2 id="1-Introduction"><a href="#1-Introduction" class="headerlink" title="1 Introduction"></a>1 Introduction</h2><p>Exceptions on studying abroad of international students had shifted sharply due to the pandemic in 2020. The working opportunity, educational quality and leisure lifestyle are all attractive to Chinese international students pursuing a postgraduate study in Australia (DESE, 2020). Their rationale for choosing Australia to continue higher degree study is not only limited to the reputation of the university, but also for the unique experience in another country.</p><p>However, after the outbreak of COVID-19, many international students experienced the lockdown for months. They may also be unsure about their future working plan in Australia due to the uncertainty in the post-pandemic stage. Furthermore, for international students without a Permanent Residency Visa, finding a formal job is hard. In addition, the positions for language- related occupations significantly declined after the pandemic (RBA, 2021). Encountering such change, most international students felt hard to face. Thus, this interview report aims to provide specific guidelines for Applied Linguistics students who are currently resident in Melbourne, better to assist them in the study and future work choice.</p><p>This report contains several sections. First, the methodology will be presented, including the information of the four interviewees and the method of the interview. Follow by the findings around three themes (studying experience, social life and working plan). Finally, this report provides recommendations to improve studying abroad life for international students living in Melbourne.</p><h2 id="2-Methodology"><a href="#2-Methodology" class="headerlink" title="2 Methodology"></a>2 Methodology</h2><h2 id="2-1-Partcipants"><a href="#2-1-Partcipants" class="headerlink" title="2.1 Partcipants"></a>2.1 Partcipants</h2><p>The information of participants shows in Table 1. Four interviewees are international students from China, including three female and one male. They all came to Melbourne before the breakout of COVID-19 and are currently studying in the Master of Applied Linguistics program at the University of Melbourne, with one semester left before graduation. In addition, the four participants all have working experience previously.</p><h2 id="2-2-Method"><a href="#2-2-Method" class="headerlink" title="2.2 Method"></a>2.2 Method</h2><p>This research was conducted with semi-structured online interviews via Zoom in English, which lasted about 40 minutes. This interview covered 21 interview questions in four sections: background information, studying experience during the pandemic, social life experience, ex- tracurricular activities, and future working plans. These questions were sent to the interviewees in advance, and in-depth questioning would be employed when necessary during the interview. All interviews are video recorded, and four interviewers would watch the recording to find the common points and individual variance concerning the impact of COVID-19 on international students.</p><h2 id="Findings"><a href="#Findings" class="headerlink" title="Findings"></a>Findings</h2><p>Based on the interview data and analysis, four interviewers concluded the impact of the pandemic on international students from three aspects: studying experience, social activities, and future working plan.</p><h2 id="3-1-Studying-experience"><a href="#3-1-Studying-experience" class="headerlink" title="3.1 Studying experience"></a>3.1 Studying experience</h2><p>The key findings in studying experience are shown in Table 2. Although the subject delivery became online due to the pandemic, the university still provided high-quality teaching content. However, students’ challenges as the lack of face-to-face interaction led to low engagement and an inadequate learning atmosphere. Communication with teachers and peers could only be carried out via emails or social applications, decreasing communicative effectiveness.</p><h3 id="3-1-1-Advantages-of-online-learning"><a href="#3-1-1-Advantages-of-online-learning" class="headerlink" title="3.1.1 Advantages of online learning"></a>3.1.1 Advantages of online learning</h3><p>Though subjects were all delivered online due to the pandemic, most interviewees agreed that the overall teaching quality had been guaranteed. Clarisse said that online teaching could provide sufficient knowledge from subject content and homework assessments. Jasmine also put it since the content of the Applied Linguistics master program was theoretical, online learning did not impact the teaching quality.</p><p>In addition, Siri and Katrina pointed out another advantage of online study – recordings. The recordings provided opportunities for students to review the online lectures or seminars repeatedly, thus helped them better comprehend teaching content. Siri mentioned that when he could not follow the teachers in the live Zoom session, recordings helped a lot. Besides, Katrina recalled when she was confused about certain points, she told us:</p><p class="note note-primary">"I would watched the recordings again”. — Katrina</p><p>Online study also gives much freedom for students in the personal arrangement. For Katrina and Clarisse, who lived far away from the campus, the online studying saved much time on transportation, as said by Katrina “I didn’t need to get up early for class”. Moreover, the less-constrained online studying provided a transitional period for Clarrise, a freshman in the university</p><h3 id="3-1-2-Challenges-of-online-learning"><a href="#3-1-2-Challenges-of-online-learning" class="headerlink" title="3.1.2 Challenges of online learning"></a>3.1.2 Challenges of online learning</h3><p>Online learning also posed challenges to students. The most prominent one was the poor engagement. Due to the pandemic, teaching was shifted to online, which resulting in less interaction. The fundamental reasons were that most students choose to turn off their camera and keep quiet in the breakout room discussion. As pointed out by the interviewees, Katrina and Jasmine stated that it was embarrassing when no one talked during the group discussion. Siri even regarded it as a terrible experience because there were few opportunities to share ideas, and he could only listen to the teacher as a recipient. Moreover, Jasmine also mentioned that some tutors did not show their faces, making her feel that she was studying by herself.</p><p class="note note-primary">"It was really bad and awful when nobody shows their faces”. — Jasmine</p><p>Additionally, the relatively relaxed atmosphere of online learning would encourage laziness, as Katrina and Jasmine regarded in their interviews. Jasmine would always fall behind her schedule because she thought she could study whenever she wanted. Hence, the weakened learning atmosphere lead to low effectiveness in studies during the pandemic.</p><h3 id="3-1-3-Communication-with-teachers-and-classmates"><a href="#3-1-3-Communication-with-teachers-and-classmates" class="headerlink" title="3.1.3 Communication with teachers and classmates"></a>3.1.3 Communication with teachers and classmates</h3><p>Apart from the in-class discussion, student-and-student communication mainly took place in completing group assignments. To better collaborate, all interviewees would utilize social media, such as Facebook, Wechat and Messenger, to collaborate with other group members. Siri also described how his group worked collaboratively through Google Doc, which functioned as a pool to post thoughts and receive feedback from others.</p><p>However, there were some problems due to the different time zones among group members. Jasmine reported that the various time zones during online collaboration had caused problematic communication. Therefore, they preferred to form groups with Chinese students for the conve- nience of communication under similar time zone. Consequently, it will reduce opportunities for them to interact in English, resulting in losing the chance to enhance communicative ability during studying abroad.</p><p>Teacher-and-student communication mainly depended on emails. Although most intervie- wees said teachers would reply to their questions in time and give detailed answers via emails, they still recognized it as time-consuming. All participants preferred face-to-face communication on campus because they thought they could get instant feedback and have more in-depth discussions with teachers.</p><h2 id="3-2-Social-life-and-interaction"><a href="#3-2-Social-life-and-interaction" class="headerlink" title="3.2 Social life and interaction"></a>3.2 Social life and interaction</h2><p>Table 3 shows the key findings in social life during the pandemic. Although the University’s online activities were not attractive, the interviewees were still willing to attend some online academic activities. For challenges in daily lives, international students faced difficulties in buying living resources due to the lockdown. Also, the low engagement and security issue made them feel anxious to go out and make new friends.</p><h3 id="3-2-1-University-activities-and-other-events"><a href="#3-2-1-University-activities-and-other-events" class="headerlink" title="3.2.1 University activities and other events"></a>3.2.1 University activities and other events</h3><p>Due to the lockdown, it was hard for the interviewees to visit friends or participate in outdoor activities. As they reported, the most common relaxation activity was cooking at home. Since the low attraction of the University’s online activities, they were not willing to engage. As pointed out by interviewees, activities like “Doing Yoga Together” lost attraction after becoming online. However, they still would like to join in some online academic activities. Clarisse mentioned that she attended the online Academic English Tutoring, as noted by her:</p><p class="note note-primary">"In this case, I could improve my language skills and engage in a meaningful activity”. — Clarisse</p><h3 id="3-2-2-Challenges-in-daily-lives-during-the-pandemic"><a href="#3-2-2-Challenges-in-daily-lives-during-the-pandemic" class="headerlink" title="3.2.2 Challenges in daily lives during the pandemic"></a>3.2.2 Challenges in daily lives during the pandemic</h3><p>When it came to challenges in daily life,all four interviewees mentioned that their ability to make shopping plans improved during the pandemic. For example, Jasmine stated that she declined the shopping frequency to once a week due to the lockdown, so she had to buy many glossaries every time. Similarly, Clarrise and Katrina, who lived far away from the city, had to make appropriate lists to ensure they would not waste time in shopping. Siri also mentioned the reason why he chose to go shopping once a week:</p><p class="note note-primary">“Only by reducing the time in public places could reduce the likelihood of infection during the pandemic.” — Siri</p><p>Some of our interviewees met other difficulties in their daily life such as public transport when going outside. For example, during the pandemic, the tightened public transportation policy made interviewees reduce the frequency of going outside, decreasing their interaction with others. As Jasmine mentioned:</p><p class="note note-primary">"When public transportation is restricted during lockdown, taking a tram has become the only way, leading to increased transportation costs and travel time” — Jasmine</p><h3 id="3-2-3-Daily-interactions-in-life"><a href="#3-2-3-Daily-interactions-in-life" class="headerlink" title="3.2.3 Daily interactions in life"></a>3.2.3 Daily interactions in life</h3><p>According to the interviewees’ daily interactions during the pandemic, they mainly reached their friends through social media, such as WeChat and Messenger. This deeply reduced their willingness to meet new friends. It was like how Jasmine pointed out: &gt; “all social activities were shifted online, it’s hard to make real new friends when we were not face-to-face”.<br>In addition, during the pandemic, the opportunities of interacting with the local people and emerging in the authentic local activities became less, Siri and Jasmine admitted their integration into Australian culture was affected, which failed their expectation to have more experience in another society. However, Katrina and Clarisse still had interactions with locals since they all lived in homestay. Katrina expressed such a wonderful experience as, “it’s lucky for me to live with locals and engage in the local culture, sometimes, my host, hostess and I with my roommates watching movies at home”. For Clarisse, staying in the host family was similar to Katrina, which made her enjoyable at home, as reported by Clarisse,</p><p class="note note-primary">“I get along well with my hostess and we talked to each other every single day”.</p><h2 id="3-3-Future-working-plan"><a href="#3-3-Future-working-plan" class="headerlink" title="3.3 Future working plan"></a>3.3 Future working plan</h2><p>Table 4 shows the key findings in the future working plan. All participants mentioned that finding a part-time job or an internship was extremely hard because the pandemic caused fewer employments in the language-related areas. Therefore, they mainly focus on professional knowledge and job certifications for their future work preparation.</p><h3 id="3-3-1-Job-opportunities-in-Australia"><a href="#3-3-1-Job-opportunities-in-Australia" class="headerlink" title="3.3.1 Job opportunities in Australia"></a>3.3.1 Job opportunities in Australia</h3><p>All four interviewees reported that the pandemic had affected their plan of finding an internship or a part-time job in Australia. For example, Katrina claimed that she had lost her part-time job as a volunteer teacher due to the budget cut in the pandemic. For Jasmine, she could hardly find an internship in Australia after the lockdown. Also, Siri mentioned two reasons that he gave up finding internships in Australia: Firstly, he believed that job opportunities have decreased after the pandemic, making it difficult to find relevant positions in Melbourne; Secondly, it was for safety reasons.</p><p class="note note-primary">"I’m worried to get affected if I go out to work, and no one would take care of me if I got sick” — Siri</p><p>Unlike the other three participants, compared to finding a job, Clarisse would focus more on learning since she did not have much language-related background. Accumulating professional knowledge was her primary goal in her early stage of linguistic learning.</p><h3 id="3-3-2-Preparation-for-future-work"><a href="#3-3-2-Preparation-for-future-work" class="headerlink" title="3.3.2 Preparation for future work"></a>3.3.2 Preparation for future work</h3><p>Talking about preparing for future work, all four participants reported that an essential thing is accumulating professional knowledge. For example, some subjects in the Master of Applied of Linguistics program prepared them well for their future works. Siri and Jasmine believe that subjects like Second Language Acquisition cover relevant professional knowledge and practical skills. As Jasmine claimed:</p><p class="note note-primary">“I can benefit a lot from Second Language Acquisition, and Language Curriculum Design” — Jasmine</p><p>Most interviewees said that they had obtained the qualification certificate for Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages (TESOL). Besides the professional certification, improving language-related working experience is also essential. For example, Jasmine and Katrina prefer to find a job in Melbourne to increase their teaching skills. Jasmine plans to use the summer term to work as a teaching assistant in a private education intuition. She believed that having overseas teaching experience will greatly help her find a job in China.</p><h2 id="Recommendations-for-students-and-staff"><a href="#Recommendations-for-students-and-staff" class="headerlink" title="Recommendations for students and staff"></a>Recommendations for students and staff</h2><h2 id="4-1-Common-themes-of-the-interviews"><a href="#4-1-Common-themes-of-the-interviews" class="headerlink" title="4.1 Common themes of the interviews"></a>4.1 Common themes of the interviews</h2><p>In studying during the pandemic, the interviewees reported the online learning quality is generally ‘good’. For example, the content of most subjects during online learning is still guaranteed since the arrangement and assignment are suitable and attractive for students in this program. Also, remote learning enables students to save time in transportation. In contrast, due to the limited communication between students and teachers and students with other peers, it’s hard to solve some problems in learning in time.</p><p>As for social life and other activities in Melbourne, the reality is more disappointing due to the lockdown. All four interviewees told us that they had imagined to know local friends and taking part in activities on campus. However, the pandemic and the following lockdown stopped all face-to-face activities, so most international students have to stay at home. Besides studying, they reported there was hardly anything for them to do.</p><p>Finally, participants recognized that some subjects in the master program are useful. In terms of future working plan and finding internships in Australia, they felt that it is tough for them to find a suitable position, especially during the pandemic when many industries cut the budget and fired employees. So, most of the interviewees would not consider staying in Australia after they graduate due to the impact of COVID-19.</p><h2 id="4-2-General-recommendations"><a href="#4-2-General-recommendations" class="headerlink" title="4.2 General recommendations"></a>4.2 General recommendations</h2><p>Based on previous findings and reflections from the four interviewers, the suggestions for further students in the School of Language and Linguistics are listed as following:</p><h3 id="4-2-1-Recommendations-for-students"><a href="#4-2-1-Recommendations-for-students" class="headerlink" title="4.2.1 Recommendations for students"></a>4.2.1 Recommendations for students</h3><p>For studying:</p><ul><li>preview and familiarize with the teaching content before the lecture </li><li>turn on the camera and engage in discussions and online lecturing</li><li>make good use of recording and online discussion boards iv) keep good communication with teachers and fellow students</li></ul><p>For social life during the post-pandemic era:</p><ul><li>expand social life through school activities (e.g.,UMSU activities) </li><li>keep in touch with friends in Melbourne</li></ul><p>For future work plan:</p><ul><li>settle a clear goal for future job</li><li>preparing for future job employment during the studying of master’s degree (e.g.,certificate<br>and job-related skills)</li><li>try to find a part-time job or an internship in language-related areas</li></ul><h4 id="4-2-2-Recommendations-for-staff"><a href="#4-2-2-Recommendations-for-staff" class="headerlink" title="4.2.2 Recommendations for staff"></a>4.2.2 Recommendations for staff</h4><ul><li>turn on the cameras when teaching in Zoom sessions</li><li>improve the opportunities of communication and engagement (e.g.,organize more breakout<br>room sessions) during teaching</li><li>focus more on the job-related skills and English language ability in some subjects, like<br>Professional Literacies or Intercultural Communication</li><li>subjects should match with the future job expectations (e.g.,for TESOL, the elective subjects<br>should emphasize more on teaching English as a second language)</li><li>provide more subject information on the website of the School of Languages and Linguistics to help students better set their study plan</li></ul><h2 id="5-Conclusions-and-outlook"><a href="#5-Conclusions-and-outlook" class="headerlink" title="5 Conclusions and outlook"></a>5 Conclusions and outlook</h2><p>This interview report presents the impact of the pandemic on international students in Australia. It reveals various challenges that international students encountered, including studying, social life and working plan. Based on the interviews, practical recommendations are provided for students and staff in the School of Languages and Linguistics. However, the sample size of the current study is limited for proposing general recommendations. Moreover, all interviews were online due to the influence of post-pandemic, which may influence the authenticity of this study. In conclusion, this report serves as a typical case for international students to help them improve their studying abroad life during the post-pandemic stage in Australia.</p><h2 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference"></a>Reference</h2><p>Department of Education, Skills and Employment. (2020). Student visa holders in and outside Australia in 2020. <a href="https://internationaleducation.gov.au/research/Research-Snapshots/Documents/RS_VisaHoldersMarch2020.pdf">https://internationaleducation.gov.au/research/Research-Snapshots/Documents/RS_VisaHoldersMarch2020.pdf</a></p><p>Reserve Bank of Australia. (2021). The COVID-19 Outbreak and Australia’s Education and Tourism Exports. <a href="https://www.rba.gov.au/publications/bulletin/2020/dec/the-covid-19-outbreak-and-australias-education-and-tourism-exports.html">https://www.rba.gov.au/publications/bulletin/2020/dec/the-covid-19-outbreak-and-australias-education-and-tourism-exports.html</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>interview</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Response to Graduate Attributes</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/20/response/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/20/response/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Response-to-Graduate-Attributes-PhD-Supervision"><a href="#Response-to-Graduate-Attributes-PhD-Supervision" class="headerlink" title="Response to Graduate Attributes: PhD Supervision"></a>Response to Graduate Attributes: PhD Supervision</h1><h2 id="1-Academic-skills"><a href="#1-Academic-skills" class="headerlink" title="1. Academic skills"></a>1. Academic skills</h2><h3 id="1-1-Ability-in-academic-writing"><a href="#1-1-Ability-in-academic-writing" class="headerlink" title="1.1. Ability in academic writing"></a>1.1. Ability in academic writing</h3><p>After successfully completing a bachelor’s degree in English Language and Linguistics at Xi’an International Studies University, and as a current master student in Applied Linguistics at the University of Melbourne, I have been trained to individually conduct academic writing and critical reading. I have<br>high score in honour thesis (86/100) and have successfully published an academic paper on a linguistic journal in 2019.</p><h3 id="1-2-Relevant-prior-research-and-or-professional-experience"><a href="#1-2-Relevant-prior-research-and-or-professional-experience" class="headerlink" title="1.2 Relevant prior research and/or professional experience"></a>1.2 Relevant prior research and/or professional experience</h3><p>As an Applied Linguistics major, I have experience in being a teaching assistant (TA) in university subjects and have tutored two subjects in VCE (English Language and Chinese Second Language) in the year 2021. Besides these teaching experience, I have considerable research experience in the field of pragmatics and discourse analysis. For example, the topic of my honour thesis is about analysing the impact of English Debate in English classroom in Chinese university with the methodology of discourse analysis and quantitative statistics.</p><h3 id="1-3-Understanding-of-the-research-question-to-be-explored"><a href="#1-3-Understanding-of-the-research-question-to-be-explored" class="headerlink" title="1.3 Understanding of the research question to be explored"></a>1.3 Understanding of the research question to be explored</h3><p>In my proposed PhD topic, I clearly address six research questions around pragmatics competence and interactional competence. All six research questions are related to the measurement of interactional competence and are all closed related to the theoretical framework in assessing second language pragmatics.</p><h3 id="1-4-Prior-academic-performance-and-if-relevant-professional-qualifications"><a href="#1-4-Prior-academic-performance-and-if-relevant-professional-qualifications" class="headerlink" title="1.4 Prior academic performance and, if relevant, professional qualifications"></a>1.4 Prior academic performance and, if relevant, professional qualifications</h3><p>I have published an academic paper related to learning motivations for Chinese ESL learners on Oversea English Journal during my bachelor’s degree. And I have considerable experience as a research assistant in the Australian Research Canter in linguistics and cross-cultural study. During my bachelor’s degree study and master’s degree, my WAM is all H1(85.8 for undergraduate study and 83 for master’s degree<br>in current progress). I have proposed a project in measuring interactional competence as the thesis in master’s degree in 2021, which is directly links to my future PhD topic, I believe this can solid my research foundations in academic preparation for PhD study.</p><h2 id="2-Preictally-Grounded"><a href="#2-Preictally-Grounded" class="headerlink" title="2. Preictally Grounded"></a>2. Preictally Grounded</h2><h3 id="2-1-Motivation-and-capacity-to-complete-the-course-in-a-timely-manner"><a href="#2-1-Motivation-and-capacity-to-complete-the-course-in-a-timely-manner" class="headerlink" title="2.1 Motivation and capacity to complete the course in a timely manner"></a>2.1 Motivation and capacity to complete the course in a timely manner</h3><p>The reason why I want to apply for PhD study is that I hold passion in second language pragmatics since it is related to how to use language resources in daily communication, which I believe is essential to explore as a linguistics major and a multi-language speaker myself. Overall, during my past study experience in both undergraduate and graduate study, finishing tasks with proper time management skills is important, especially when I was conducting my honour thesis project within a year independently, I improved a lot in planning and adjusting myself in finishing a huge research project.</p><h3 id="2-2-Competitiveness-for-scholarship-allocation-and-the-ability-of-the-Faculty-to-provide-the-appropriate-supervision-facilities-and-resources-for-your-intended-project"><a href="#2-2-Competitiveness-for-scholarship-allocation-and-the-ability-of-the-Faculty-to-provide-the-appropriate-supervision-facilities-and-resources-for-your-intended-project" class="headerlink" title="2.2 Competitiveness for scholarship allocation; and the ability of the Faculty to provide the appropriate supervision, facilities and resources for your intended project"></a>2.2 Competitiveness for scholarship allocation; and the ability of the Faculty to provide the appropriate supervision, facilities and resources for your intended project</h3><p>My average WAM and past research performance are capable in applying scholarship; as for my proposed topic, in school of language and linguistics there are several supervisors who are available to supervise the research in language testing and second language pragmatics (e.g., Carsten Roever; Jason Fan, Ute Knoch). Moreover, within the Language Testing Centre, there is huge potential in promoting pragmatics assessment in large scale language tests which directly matches with my topic.</p><h3 id="2-3-Have-obtained-the-endorsement-of-a-prospective-supervisor"><a href="#2-3-Have-obtained-the-endorsement-of-a-prospective-supervisor" class="headerlink" title="2.3 Have obtained the endorsement of a prospective supervisor"></a>2.3 Have obtained the endorsement of a prospective supervisor</h3><p>Yes, Carsten Roever would be my supervisor.</p><h3 id="2-4-A-Master’s-degree-in-a-relevant-discipline-which-includes-a-substantial-research-component"><a href="#2-4-A-Master’s-degree-in-a-relevant-discipline-which-includes-a-substantial-research-component" class="headerlink" title="2.4 A Master’s degree in a relevant discipline which includes a substantial research component,"></a>2.4 A Master’s degree in a relevant discipline which includes a substantial research component,</h3><p>equivalent to at least 25% of one year of full-time study and achieved a minimum weighted average of 75% or (University of Melbourne) equivalent, with a minimum result of 80% for the research component<br>My weighted average is 83% (in process) and I would conduct a 25-points research module (minor thesis for applied linguistics) under the supervision of Carsten Roever in 2021.</p><h3 id="2-5-English-Language-Criteria"><a href="#2-5-English-Language-Criteria" class="headerlink" title="2.5 English Language Criteria"></a>2.5 English Language Criteria</h3><p>I have studied in Melbourne for two year and my IELTS score is 7.5 with the average band of 7.0.</p><h2 id="3-Socially-responsible"><a href="#3-Socially-responsible" class="headerlink" title="3. Socially responsible"></a>3. Socially responsible</h2><h3 id="3-1-A-high-regard-for-human-rights-social-inclusion-ethics-and-the-environment"><a href="#3-1-A-high-regard-for-human-rights-social-inclusion-ethics-and-the-environment" class="headerlink" title="3.1 A high regard for human rights, social inclusion, ethics and the environment"></a>3.1 A high regard for human rights, social inclusion, ethics and the environment</h3><p>For my personal experience, I had conducted a research project to help Chinese minority group to protect their cultural heritage, so I believe I’m capable enough to consider human right issues. I also attended a number of subjects concerning human right issues and historical development during my past study, such as Australian History, American History. During this process, I gained a deep understanding in how to interpret events (e.g., feminism issues) under certain social background and the meaning of human right in history.</p><h3 id="3-2-Ability-to-work-collaboratively-with-people-from-diverse-linguistic-and-cultural-backgrounds"><a href="#3-2-Ability-to-work-collaboratively-with-people-from-diverse-linguistic-and-cultural-backgrounds" class="headerlink" title="3.2 Ability to work collaboratively with people from diverse linguistic and cultural backgrounds"></a>3.2 Ability to work collaboratively with people from diverse linguistic and cultural backgrounds</h3><p>During my past research experience, I have collaborated with oversea researchers and successfully helped to manage a huge cross-cultural linguistic study as a research assistant. In addition, during my master’s degree, I often helped other members who have diverse cultural and language background in my team to fulfill the group project as a group leader.</p><p>Requirement URL:<br><a href="https://study.unimelb.edu.au/find/courses/graduate/doctor-of-philosophy-arts/entry-requirements/">https://study.unimelb.edu.au/find/courses/graduate/doctor-of-philosophy-arts/entry-requirements/</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cover Letter</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/18/cover-letter/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/18/cover-letter/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Cover-Letter"><a href="#Cover-Letter" class="headerlink" title="Cover Letter"></a>Cover Letter</h1><p>Dear Associate Professor Carsten Roever,</p><p>I’m Rena (Wei Gao), a current student in the Master of Applied Linguistics at the University of Melbourne. I’ve developed my keen interests in L2 pragmatics, so I hope to pursue further study in this area. I have conducted a research project as master thesis to measure the listener responses and interactional competence of study abroad Chinese L1 speakers in Australian universities. During my undergraduate study (2019), I published a Chinese paper on investing English L2 learning motivation in Chinese universities among non-English majors.</p><p>Please allow me to introduce my PhD topic briefly, and I believe my proposed topic matches with your research area. After doing a preliminary study, I noticed that improving interactional competence in language expression is essential in developing pragmatics ability for study abroad students. In my research, I would mainly focus on the development of interactional practices (e.g., email in an academic setting; the expression on social media, chat with native speakers and etc.) during study abroad and applying a cross-linguistics approach to analyze the impact of L1 when developing L2 competence. Chinese L1 students in Australian universities would be the main population of this study. Also, I would apply discourse analysis to provide both qualitative and quantitative empirical data in this research.</p><p>I’ve learned that you have published widely in these research areas, especially in areas related to L2 pragmatics and interactional competence. I believe my proposed topic is suitable for you to supervise. I wonder in the next available intake (2022), do you have a plan to recruit new PhD students, and will I have the honor to work with you under your supervision? For your further consideration, I attached my CV, 2500-words Research proposal and response to attributes.</p><p>Thank you for your time reading this email and I look forward to hearing from you.</p><p>Kind regards, Wei Gao</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>job_set</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/18/cv/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/18/cv/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Resume"><a href="#Resume" class="headerlink" title="Resume"></a>Resume</h1><p>Here is my CV</p><div><p>You can download it! <p> <a href="/assets/files/CV-converted.pdf" download="CV-converted.pdf" style="background: #32373c;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Download<a/></div><p><object classid="clsid:CA8A9780-280D-11CF-A24D-444553540000" width="100%" height="100%" border="0"><!--IE--><br>      <param name="_Version" value="65539"><br>      <param name="_ExtentX" value="20108"><br>      <param name="_ExtentY" value="10866"><br>      <param name="_StockProps" value="0"><br>      <param name="SRC" value="/assets/files/CV-converted.pdf"><br><embed src="/assets/files/Wei-Gao-PL-PhD-CV.pdf" width="100%" height="800" href="/assets/files/CV-converted.pdf"></embed><!--FF--><br></object></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>job_set</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Opinion Piece</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/15/opinion-piece/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/15/opinion-piece/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Why-should-you-learn-a-language-with-smartphone-apps"><a href="#Why-should-you-learn-a-language-with-smartphone-apps" class="headerlink" title="Why should you learn a language with smartphone apps?"></a>Why should you learn a language with smartphone apps?</h1><div align=center><img src="/assets/images/op1.png" width="600" height="300" style="margin-bottom: 20px;" /></div><p>Want to learn a new language but don’t have enough time? Always feel painful when stat to learn a new language? Smartphone <a href="https://www.lingualift.com/blog/best-language-learning-apps/">language learning applications</a> or apps create a fun way for language learners. </p><p>Among the vast apps on smartphones, one of the most powerful developments in education is language learning apps. The nature of smartphone apps enables learners to absorb new knowledge anywhere and anytime.</p><p>It’s better than nothing. Personally speaking, when I am waiting for a tram, I would open <a href="https://www.duolingo.com/courses">Duolingo</a> on my smartphone and grasp some new Spanish words in just 10 minutes. This language learning activity can happen every day on my way back home. </p><p>As a way of <a href="https://www.education.vic.gov.au/languagesonline/">online language learning</a>, <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/elt/blog/2018/05/18/using-smartphones-language-learning/">researchers</a> believe language learning apps have a better <a href="https://teaching.utoronto.ca/teaching-support/course-design/developing-learning-outcomes/what-are-learning-outcomes/">outcome</a>. Language learning apps have a better learning atmosphere in the online learning process. For example, <a href="https://quizlet.com/zh-cn">Quizlet</a>, it provides flashcards and quizzes for learners to grasp new vocabulary in a fun way. Compared to traditional <a href="http://www.ascd.org/publications/books/121007/chapters/Looking-at-Classroom-Teaching-and-Learning.aspx">classroom teaching and learning approach</a>, language learning apps provide a range of attractive tasks for learners to continue learning in daily life. And it can be a very rewarding way to learn new vocabulary.   </p><h2 id="Motivation-is-key"><a href="#Motivation-is-key" class="headerlink" title="Motivation is key"></a>Motivation is key</h2><div align=center><img src="/assets/images/op2.png" width="600" height="350" /></div><p>These language learning apps are all free and communicative to attract new learner’s interest. Some apps have <a href="https://www.trueeducationpartnerships.com/schools/gamification-in-education/">gamification</a> and <a href="https://www.whatiselt.com/single-post/2018/08/23/What-is-the-Communicative-Approach">communication</a> functions to inspire learners to learn a new language in a <a href="https://www.brendansailing.org/programs.html">virtual community</a>. </p><p>Language learners can share, comment, and <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/gb/files/4415/8594/0876/Giving_Feedback_minipaper_ONLINE.pdf">receive feedback</a> on their learning progress from other learners on language apps with this function. </p><p>Don’t worry about starting with a hard beginning. The level of learning can be flexible according to the learner’s primary level. When a language learner begins to study a new language, the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/computer-science/adaptive-algorithm">adaptive algorithms</a> will suit the learner’s learning level. Then it adjusts the tasks each day. In this way, learners can organize their study and follow their learning speed actively. </p><p>Particular attention to <a href="https://blog.duolingo.com/how-we-learn-how-you-learn/">tools and technology</a> on these apps can provide a better quality of daily practice. You can find the most suitable pace to learn. </p><p>These apps offer opportunities to remember vocabulary and practise grammar. New vocabulary and grammar points for various learners can be suitable according to individual progress. As a result, their learning motivation can be consistently enhanced in daily practice. </p><p>Language learning apps can make language learners fulfilled after finishing daily tasks. Most language learning apps would remind you each day to do the task. Then it provides virtual rewards after sharing your progress on social media like Twitter or Instagram or virtual learning communities. </p><h2 id="Informal-learning-feels-more-relaxation"><a href="#Informal-learning-feels-more-relaxation" class="headerlink" title="Informal learning feels more relaxation"></a>Informal learning feels more relaxation</h2><div style="width: 500px;">    <img src="/assets/images/op3.png" align="left" width="200" height="300" style="padding: 0; margin-right:20px"><br /></div><p>As an <a href="https://trainingindustry.com/glossary/informal-learning/">informal learning</a> activity, learning through smartphone apps is interesting.</p><p>Language learning apps are different from <a href="https://www.learnupon.com/blog/formal-and-informal-learning/">formal learning</a>, such as <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/41948666?seq=1">in-class teaching and learning</a>, or <a href="https://www.indeed.com/career-advice/career-development/what-is-vocational-training">vocational training</a> on language with planned sessions.<br>This kind of learning enables language learners to be exposed to a new language with high frequency in daily life. The daily task, such as remembering vocabulary and <a href="https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Browse/Search:sentences%20matching">sentence matching</a>, would consume no more than a half-hour, usually 15 to 2.</p><p>This pattern encourages learners to dive into language learning every day. Since the chunks of time needed are so small, it can be done in the coffee queue, allowing the users to learn without sacrificing other things in their lives. It can help you understand new words and some basic constructions, but it isn’t going to push you to leap into a ‘conversation’ in a new language.</p><p><a href="https://www.duolingo.com/courses">Duolingo</a> is one of the most famous language learning apps for touching a <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/second-language-1691930">second language</a> on smartphones. It offers learners a skill tree of lessons that use listening exercises, flashcards, and multiple-choice questions. Learners can drill new words, phrases, and sentences in the <a href="https://www.teachingenglish.org.uk/article/target-language">target learning language</a>. Without time-consuming activities, daily practice on smartphone apps within half an hour can guarantee a stable improvement in a new language after months of studying.</p><p>Receiving feedback from the online virtual community is non-threatening at all. This learning environment can reduce the <a href="https://hbr.org/2002/03/the-anxiety-of-learning">anxiety</a> of learning a new language for most learners. Language teachers always give feedback with a ‘right’ or ‘wrong’ judgment after practice in a formal class. Learners may feel embarrassed in this process. Their <a href="https://theeducationhub.org.nz/motivation/">learning motivation</a> may be reduced after getting the marks and ‘correct answers’ from their teachers. </p><p>However, through language learning apps, co-learners often present their opinion and suggestions instead of definite judgements. Without the direct link to answers or grades, users would hold high interest in learning language learning apps in the long run. </p><p>For new language learners, touching the basic knowledge in a fun way can be helpful at the start. Language learning needs consistent effort. In the long run, you can develop language learning into a daily hobbit without spending much time, just like me. </p><p>Don’t hesitate, pick up your phone, start your new language journey now!  </p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>opinion piece</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction and Reflection on opinion piece</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/14/Introduction-and-reflection-on-opinion-piece/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/14/Introduction-and-reflection-on-opinion-piece/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction-of-opinion-piece"><a href="#Introduction-of-opinion-piece" class="headerlink" title="Introduction of opinion piece:"></a>Introduction of opinion piece:</h2><p>This opinion piece is about the usage of language learning apps on smartphones and their advantages in assisting language learners. It can function as a ‘fun starter’ for new beginners. I often heard a lot of learners complaining about how hard they felt when touching a new language. Regarding my personal experience, it occurs to me that as a linguistics major, I can introduce this way of learning to the general audience helping them to learn. </p><p>This opinion piece expresses the subjective opinion from the author instead of an academic argumentation overall. Compared with the voice of an academic paper, this opinion piece is a different genre needing a more comprehensible style and a credible voice. To draft this opinion piece, I read plenty of articles on The Conversations to familiarize the professional style. </p><p><a href="/2021/05/15/opinion-piece/" style="background: #E74C3C;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Link to article<a/></p><h2 id="Reflection-of-opinion-piece"><a href="#Reflection-of-opinion-piece" class="headerlink" title="Reflection of opinion piece:"></a>Reflection of opinion piece:</h2><ul><li>Learning to adopt different genre</li></ul><p>The genre of an opinion piece is quite different from an academic paper which I am familiar with. This requires me to transfer my writing style and learn how to suit the voice of different audiences in writing. So, in order to learn the style and language traits of this opinion piece, I almost read about 20 articles on The Conversations and The Guardians. Then I realized the biggest bias for me is to come up with an attractive beginning and ending since for most academic papers the beginning and ending are usually introductions and conclusions without the requirements to entertain or lure the audience to your article. But after drafting this article, I realize one thing is that the good beginning is half of a good piece for the general public. To better achieve this goal, I employ open interrogatives at the beginning of this opinion piece and provide an example related to myself in learning through smartphone apps to echo with the audience who may be interested in learning a language through smartphone apps as well.</p><ul><li>Get rid of previous writing conventions</li></ul><p>During my past paper drafting, I would employ a lot of jargon or terms in the Linguistics field. Also, the sentences need to be complex and comprehensive in general. However, for this assignment, the writing conventions are different since the writing purpose and the target audience are all shifted. For example, I tried to divide long and complex sentences into short ones to make the passage more understandable. Also, I put several hyperlinks in the articles to help readers to understand the terms in this article. Hence, to attract reader’s interest, some fun pictures were inserted in the articles to make this passage more attractive.</p><ul><li>Challenges in drafting</li></ul><p>To be honest, there were some barriers when I was drafting this article. This topic expects the target readers to have some general background knowledge in second language learning while I try to break the gap between the academic concepts in second language acquisition and the acceptability of the general audience. In general, I wanted to present the necessity of language learning apps in current e-life and two advantages of how they can promote language learning in a spare time and in a leisure way. But the focus needs to be more constant, and the explanation of the key information needs to be more focused due to the 800 words limitation, so I cut several sentences and unnecessary points after finishing the first draft.</p><ul><li>New thoughts after receiving the feedback</li></ul><p>Also, some thoughts occur to me after receiving the feedback of this opinion piece as well. For example, more editing is still needed when drafting an opinion piece. Also, even minor typos may cause misunderstanding for the general readers. So proofreading and careful editing is necessary in this kind of writing.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>opinion piece</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
