<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction and Reflection on opinion piece</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/25/Introduction-and-reflection-on-opinion-piece/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/25/Introduction-and-reflection-on-opinion-piece/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction-of-opinion-piece"><a href="#Introduction-of-opinion-piece" class="headerlink" title="Introduction of opinion piece:"></a>Introduction of opinion piece:</h2><p>This opinion piece is about the usage of language learning apps on smartphones and their advantages in assisting language learners. It can function as a ‘fun starter’ for new beginners. I often heard a lot of learners complaining about how hard they felt when touching a new language. Regarding my personal experience, it occurs to me that as a linguistics major, I can introduce this way of learning to the general audience helping them to learn. </p><p>This opinion piece expresses the subjective opinion from the author instead of an academic argumentation overall. Compared with the voice of an academic paper, this opinion piece is a different genre needing a more comprehensible style and a credible voice. To draft this opinion piece, I read plenty of articles on The Conversations to familiarize the professional style. </p><h2 id="Reflection-of-opinion-piece"><a href="#Reflection-of-opinion-piece" class="headerlink" title="Reflection of opinion piece:"></a>Reflection of opinion piece:</h2><ul><li>Learning to adopt different genre</li></ul><p>The genre of an opinion piece is quite different from an academic paper which I am familiar with. This requires me to transfer my writing style and learn how to suit the voice of different audiences in writing. So, in order to learn the style and language traits of this opinion piece, I almost read about 20 articles on The Conversations and The Guardians. Then I realized the biggest bias for me is to come up with an attractive beginning and ending since for most academic papers the beginning and ending are usually introductions and conclusions without the requirements to entertain or lure the audience to your article. But after drafting this article, I realize one thing is that the good beginning is half of a good piece for the general public. To better achieve this goal, I employ open interrogatives at the beginning of this opinion piece and provide an example related to myself in learning through smartphone apps to echo with the audience who may be interested in learning a language through smartphone apps as well.</p><ul><li>Get rid of previous writing conventions</li></ul><p>During my past paper drafting, I would employ a lot of jargon or terms in the Linguistics field. Also, the sentences need to be complex and comprehensive in general. However, for this assignment, the writing conventions are different since the writing purpose and the target audience are all shifted. For example, I tried to divide long and complex sentences into short ones to make the passage more understandable. Also, I put several hyperlinks in the articles to help readers to understand the terms in this article. Hence, to attract reader’s interest, some fun pictures were inserted in the articles to make this passage more attractive.</p><ul><li>Challenges in drafting</li></ul><p>To be honest, there were some barriers when I was drafting this article. This topic expects the target readers to have some general background knowledge in second language learning while I try to break the gap between the academic concepts in second language acquisition and the acceptability of the general audience. In general, I wanted to present the necessity of language learning apps in current e-life and two advantages of how they can promote language learning in a spare time and in a leisure way. But the focus needs to be more constant, and the explanation of the key information needs to be more focused due to the 800 words limitation, so I cut several sentences and unnecessary points after finishing the first draft.</p><ul><li>New thoughts after receiving the feedback</li></ul><p>Also, some thoughts occur to me after receiving the feedback of this opinion piece as well. For example, more editing is still needed when drafting an opinion piece. Also, even minor typos may cause misunderstanding for the general readers. So proofreading and careful editing is necessary in this kind of writing.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>opinion-piece</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction and Reflection on interview report</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/24/Introduction-and-reflection-on-the-Interview-report/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/24/Introduction-and-reflection-on-the-Interview-report/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- ![](/images/activity-1-paragraph-image1.jpeg) --><img src="/assets/images/article-intro.jpeg" width="748" height="440" /><h2 id="Introduction-of-the-interview-report"><a href="#Introduction-of-the-interview-report" class="headerlink" title="Introduction of the interview report:"></a>Introduction of the interview report:</h2><p>This report investigates the impact of the COVID-19 on international students who are resident in Melbourne and how it changed their style of studying, social interaction and future work plan. All four interviewees are Master students from the School of Language and Linguistics. The interview adopts the semi-structured way to see their change and attitude towards the online learning and their social life as well as their future work choice in year 2020.</p><p>During the process of completing this assignment, four members in our group collaborative well although we basically depend on online communicate software to update on each other. Before we actually conducting the interview, I settled the topic and focus of this interview, then all the group members brainstormed on the interview questions collaboratively. Then, each of us is responsible for one part in the report and contacted our interviewees respectively.<br>During the process of each interview, four group members would all be in the Zoom session and after completing the interview, all members would listen to the recording again and find some interesting points to address in the report. Finally, after drafting the report, we improved the ability of collaborative work, especially in writing and conducting interview.</p><h2 id="Reflection-of-the-interview-report"><a href="#Reflection-of-the-interview-report" class="headerlink" title="Reflection of the interview report:"></a>Reflection of the interview report:</h2><ul><li>Identify the interview focus is essential</li></ul><p>Before conducting this assignment, I have interview experience when I was the Research Assistant in the Australian Center. But I mainly help to collect data and analyse discourse data instead of design an interview individually by myself. When first dived into this report, I began to wonder what is worth interviewing for international students in Australian university since I hold such an identity myself. After a reflection on my own experience in the past year, I think to interest the impact of the pandemic on international students would be interesting and meaningful. Thus, I decided to set the topic as:</p><blockquote><p> How COVID-19 Pandemic Affect Studying Abroad in Australian University: A Case of Master Students in School of Language and Linguistics</p></blockquote><ul><li>Make everyone clear about their role</li></ul><p>To be honest, this is the most challenging part for me since the other three group members don’t have any interview or analysis experience, so it makes all members understanding their role in the first place is quite difficult. So, I use several times to show them the difference between interview and conversation and how to analyse interview discourse from an objective perspective. Besides, we also marked everyone’s part in a Google Doc so that the whole group could be much clearer about the whole process and progress of the report. Even four group members mainly worked remotely due to the post-pandemic reason, but the weekly meeting went go pretty smooth.</p><ul><li>Time management is everything</li></ul><p>When the group are working on the interview and the report, there are other assignments due at the same time, and after everyone finalized their part, I would look through all the report and correct some typos and grammar mistakes. Thus, it is essential to allocate the duty in a reasonable schedule. Through this assignment, I learned how to collaborate writing and interview others professionally, including all the processes from designing interview questions to finally doing the transcript.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>interview</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction and Reflection on the job set</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/24/introduction-and-reflection-on-the-job-set/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/24/introduction-and-reflection-on-the-job-set/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Introduction-of-the-job-set"><a href="#Introduction-of-the-job-set" class="headerlink" title="Introduction of the job set:"></a>Introduction of the job set:</h2><p>This job set is mainly about my personal background and research experience in response to the requirement for PhD selection criteria in the Arts faculty of UniMelb and focuses on highlighting my research interest and advantages in perusing further study in the School and Language and Linguistics.</p><p>The set includes three parts, a Cover letter, CV and selection criteria respectively. The main purpose of the cover letter is to recommend me to the supervisor who is matching with my research interest and show my highlights in academic research and professional experience. The second part (CV) is mainly about detailed information about me, such as past educational background, publications, professional experience, research outcome and skills. Finally, the main focus of the response to selection criteria is to reflect how I meet each selection criteria in perusing for a PhD study in UniMelb. </p><div>    <a href="/assets/files/Wei-Gao-PL-PhD-CV.pdf" download="Wei-Gao-PL-PhD-CV.pdf">Rena’s Job Set👉</a>    <a href="/assets/files/Wei-Gao-PL-PhD-CV.pdf" download="Wei-Gao-PL-PhD-CV.pdf" style="background: #32373c;border-radius: 2em;color: #fff;font-size: 13px;padding: .5em 1em;border: 0;margin-left: .75em;text-decoration: none;transition: all 0.2s ease-in-out 0s;" >Download<a/></div><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Reflection-on-the-job-set"><a href="#Reflection-on-the-job-set" class="headerlink" title="Reflection on the job set:"></a>Reflection on the job set:</h2><ul><li>Challenges in designing this job set:</li></ul><p>First of all, the most challenging part in this job set is to suit myself in the requirement of assignment instead of a real PhD application. Since the genre and cover letter in the real selection is quite different with the requirements in this subject in many aspects. For example, in the CV required for a real PhD application, a section of briefly introduce proposed topic is necessary for the selection committee, while in this subject, the CV does not need to include this part. And I struggled with the different requirements a lot when I touch this job set at first.</p><ul><li>Get to work on this job set:</li></ul><p>However, after Janne’s advice and her suggestion during the several seminars, I felt much better at understanding the difference of this assignment between the real requirements in PhD application. So, I made several adjustments in drafting this job set. First, I cut several details in my CV, only kept the most relevant experience and highlights in my past research and academic experience. Also, the length of the cover letter was shortened to one page and become more concise in the whole content, and I didn’t include the research purpose which is actually required in the application. Furthermore, for the response to selection criteria, I modified a little bit on the overall structure in order to make it clearer since the requirements of the PhD selection of Arts is quite long and a lot of documents and supplementary materials are needed as well.</p><ul><li>More understanding on this kind of genre:</li></ul><p>After receiving the feedback, I realised that the Job Set has completely different purpose than the academic writing, which is short, appropriate and accurate in general tone, instead of listing much details or presenting deep understanding in certain position.</p><p>Thus, it suits me better in my future resume preparation as well as drafting for cover letter in emails to the target person (e.g. supervisor).</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>job-set</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why should you learn a language with smartphone apps?</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/15/Opinion_Piece/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/15/Opinion_Piece/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- ![](/images/activity-1-paragraph-image1.jpeg) --><img src="/assets/images/activity-1-paragraph-image1.jpeg" width="286" height="440" /><p>Want to learn a new language but don’t have enough time? Always feel painful when stat to learn a new language? Smartphone <a href="https://www.lingualift.com/blog/best-language-learning-apps/">language learning applications</a> or apps create a fun way for language learners. </p><p>Among the vast apps on smartphones, one of the most powerful developments in education is language learning apps. The nature of smartphone apps enables learners to absorb new knowledge anywhere and anytime.</p><p>It’s better than nothing. Personally speaking, when I am waiting for a tram, I would open <a href="https://www.duolingo.com/courses">Duolingo</a> on my smartphone and grasp some new Spanish words in just 10 minutes. This language learning activity can happen every day on my way back home. </p><p>As a way of <a href="https://www.education.vic.gov.au/languagesonline/">online language learning</a>, <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/elt/blog/2018/05/18/using-smartphones-language-learning/">researchers</a> believe language learning apps have a better <a href="https://teaching.utoronto.ca/teaching-support/course-design/developing-learning-outcomes/what-are-learning-outcomes/">outcome</a>. Language learning apps have a better learning atmosphere in the online learning process. For example, <a href="https://quizlet.com/zh-cn">Quizlet</a>, it provides flashcards and quizzes for learners to grasp new vocabulary in a fun way. Compared to traditional <a href="http://www.ascd.org/publications/books/121007/chapters/Looking-at-Classroom-Teaching-and-Learning.aspx">classroom teaching and learning approach</a>, language learning apps provide a range of attractive tasks for learners to continue learning in daily life. And it can be a very rewarding way to learn new vocabulary.   </p><h2 id="Motivation-is-key"><a href="#Motivation-is-key" class="headerlink" title="Motivation is key"></a>Motivation is key</h2><p>These language learning apps are all free and communicative to attract new learner’s interest. Some apps have <a href="https://www.trueeducationpartnerships.com/schools/gamification-in-education/">gamification</a> and <a href="https://www.whatiselt.com/single-post/2018/08/23/What-is-the-Communicative-Approach">communication</a> functions to inspire learners to learn a new language in a <a href="https://www.brendansailing.org/programs.html">virtual community</a>. </p><p>Language learners can share, comment, and <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/gb/files/4415/8594/0876/Giving_Feedback_minipaper_ONLINE.pdf">receive feedback</a> on their learning progress from other learners on language apps with this function. </p><p>Don’t worry about starting with a hard beginning. The level of learning can be flexible according to the learner’s primary level. When a language learner begins to study a new language, the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/computer-science/adaptive-algorithm">adaptive algorithms</a> will suit the learner’s learning level. Then it adjusts the tasks each day. In this way, learners can organize their study and follow their learning speed actively. </p><p>Particular attention to <a href="https://blog.duolingo.com/how-we-learn-how-you-learn/">tools and technology</a> on these apps can provide a better quality of daily practice. You can find the most suitable pace to learn. </p><p>These apps offer opportunities to remember vocabulary and practise grammar. New vocabulary and grammar points for various learners can be suitable according to individual progress. As a result, their learning motivation can be consistently enhanced in daily practice. </p><p>Language learning apps can make language learners fulfilled after finishing daily tasks. Most language learning apps would remind you each day to do the task. Then it provides virtual rewards after sharing your progress on social media like Twitter or Instagram or virtual learning communities. </p><h2 id="Informal-learning-feels-more-relaxation"><a href="#Informal-learning-feels-more-relaxation" class="headerlink" title="Informal learning feels more relaxation"></a>Informal learning feels more relaxation</h2><p>As an <a href="https://trainingindustry.com/glossary/informal-learning/">informal learning</a> activity, learning through smartphone apps is interesting.</p><p>Language learning apps are different from <a href="https://www.learnupon.com/blog/formal-and-informal-learning/">formal learning</a>, such as <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/41948666?seq=1">in-class teaching and learning</a>, or <a href="https://www.indeed.com/career-advice/career-development/what-is-vocational-training">vocational training</a> on language with planned sessions.<br>This kind of learning enables language learners to be exposed to a new language with high frequency in daily life. The daily task, such as remembering vocabulary and <a href="https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Browse/Search:sentences%20matching">sentence matching</a>, would consume no more than a half-hour, usually 15 to 20 minutes. </p><p>This pattern encourages learners to dive into language learning every day. Since the chunks of time needed are so small, it can be done in the coffee queue, allowing the users to learn without sacrificing other things in their lives. It can help you understand new words and some basic constructions, but it isn’t going to push you to leap into a ‘conversation’ in a new language.</p><p><a href="https://www.duolingo.com/courses">Duolingo</a> is one of the most famous language learning apps for touching a <a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/second-language-1691930">second language</a> on smartphones. It offers learners a skill tree of lessons that use listening exercises, flashcards, and multiple-choice questions. Learners can drill new words, phrases, and sentences in the <a href="https://www.teachingenglish.org.uk/article/target-language">target learning language</a>. Without time-consuming activities, daily practice on smartphone apps within half an hour can guarantee a stable improvement in a new language after months of studying.</p><p>Receiving feedback from the online virtual community is non-threatening at all. This learning environment can reduce the <a href="https://hbr.org/2002/03/the-anxiety-of-learning">anxiety</a> of learning a new language for most learners. Language teachers always give feedback with a ‘right’ or ‘wrong’ judgment after practice in a formal class. Learners may feel embarrassed in this process. Their <a href="https://theeducationhub.org.nz/motivation/">learning motivation</a> may be reduced after getting the marks and ‘correct answers’ from their teachers. </p><p>However, through language learning apps, co-learners often present their opinion and suggestions instead of definite judgements. Without the direct link to answers or grades, users would hold high interest in learning language learning apps in the long run. </p><p>For new language learners, touching the basic knowledge in a fun way can be helpful at the start. Language learning needs consistent effort. In the long run, you can develop language learning into a daily hobbit without spending much time, just like me. </p><p>Don’t hesitate, pick up your phone, start your new language journey now!  </p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>opinion-piece</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>A glance through my window</title>
    <link href="/2021/05/05/Activity-1-paragraph/"/>
    <url>/2021/05/05/Activity-1-paragraph/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- ![](/images/activity-1-paragraph-image1.jpeg) --><div style="width:500px;">            <img src="/assets/images/activity-1-paragraph-image1.jpeg" align="left" width="286" height="440" vspace="5" />            <p> This is a practice writing piece during the second seminar of Professional Literacies, about the view outside the apartment window. It is required that we need to provide a detailed description of the scene.</p></div><h2 id="The-world-through-my-window"><a href="#The-world-through-my-window" class="headerlink" title="The world through my window"></a>The world through my window</h2><p>‘It is so blue’, when I suddenly raise my head and look outside, the blue sky of Melbourne just surprises me in a minute. Living in Carlton for a quite long time,  I never noticed that the view through my apartment window can be so amazing. The RMIT building is in front of where I live, and I can see quite a lot students walking in and out with their bags and holding their books. The Yarra tram passes by with a sound of bells. Also, there are two birds resting on my balcony, the interesting thing is that my cat Ray, who really has strange fantasy of being a bird, she would imitate the sound of bird every time when she sees the birds through the window.  It is also attractive to spend some time on observing the pedestrian crossing between my apartment building and RMIT building since there are a lot of people passing. I always think that observing others is quite an interesting reflection of my inner thoughts in some degree. Taking a glance further away, I can even see Melbourne Central, although I know it is quite near where I live.  When I look back, one of my cat is staring at me, at that moment, I cannot be more felicific.  </p><h2 id="Reflection-on-this-short-piece"><a href="#Reflection-on-this-short-piece" class="headerlink" title="Reflection on this short piece:"></a>Reflection on this short piece:</h2><ul><li>What there anything you learnt from doing this activity?</li><li>What did you find challenging about it/what easy?</li><li>What sort of language did you use?</li></ul><h2 id="My-reflection"><a href="#My-reflection" class="headerlink" title="My reflection:"></a>My reflection:</h2><p>How to arrange the structure of a passage in a short time is the most important thing I learnt through this activity. After listening and reviewing on other’s piece, I realised that in the writing, personal feeling and reflection can also be linked with objective view.</p><p>Secondly, it is not a easy task to provide something complete within 20 minutes, the time pressure is also a huge challenge for me to overcome since I’m always a slow typer.</p><p>Also, considering this is a piece about daily view and scene, so what I adopt is the language to describe things instead of academic or argumentative overall.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
